It is the turbulent Sengoku period.
어지러운 전국 시대.
Warlords keep on fighting day and night over Jipangu State, where Karakuri people live.
카라쿠리인이 사는 지팡구국에서는 군웅할거하여 밤낮으로 접전이 계속되고
Karakuri martial artists were sharpening their swords, dreaming of victory and honor.
카라쿠리 무예가들도 승리와 영광을 꿈꾸며 맹렬히 싸우고 있었다.
And now, a wild hero has arrived, seeking to be the number one Karakuri martial artist!
그리고 지금, 카라쿠리 무예가 제일을 꿈꾸는 터무니없는 영웅이 탄생했다!
Musashi is here-dasu!
무사시 등장이오!
Karakuri Kengouden
카라쿠리 검호전: 무사시 로드
A man always dreams of the day
사내는 언제나 세계 한가운데서
in the center of the world to become
제일 강해질 날을
AH! AH! the strongest
아! 아! 꿈꿔라
Raise the sword of your heart high to the wide sky
마음의 칼을 넓은 하늘로 번쩍 쳐들어
Raise the curtain to the road of adventure
모험의 길의 막을 연다
A skilled swordsman roams on Jipangu State
지팡구국을 떠도는 검호
His name is Musashi, a Karakuri man
그 이름은 카라쿠리인 무사시
Go! Fight!
가라! 싸워라!
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Battles of yesterdays make you stronger today
싸웠던 어제보다도 오늘 강해진다
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
Tomorrow will be glorious
내일은 빛난다
The sound of fierce duels
격렬한 승부의 소리는
makes life dazzling
눈부신 인생
Fight the utmost with the stillness
싸우는 한껏 고요함과 함께
Martial Arts! Dual Blade Musashi
무예! 이도류 무사시
His eyes shined! Musashi!
미간이 반짝였다 무사시!!
Musashi and others went into Seto Inland Sea to find the base of the enemy, but Shingen and Kenshin were waiting for them.
무사시 일행은 적의 본거지를 찾기 위해 세토 내해에 들어가지만, 거기서 기다리고 있던 건 신겐과 켄신이었다.
Musashi and others attacked in return, but they ended up having a hard fight between the combined Shingenshin.
맞받아친 무사시 일행. 그러나 합체한 신겐신의 힘 앞에서 고전을 면치 못한다.
Charming Outlook
요염한 모습
Karakuri Shift
카라쿠리 변화이오
You let them run away?
무사시 놈들이 달아나게 두었다고?
We deeply apologize.
정말 면목이 없습니다.
I would have finished them if I was alone, but that Shingen guy got in my way and...
저 혼자서라면 확실히 해치웠을 수 있었을 테지만, 이 신겐이라는 놈이 방해해서...
What are you talking about?! You're the one who tried to take all my achievements!
뭔 소리냐! 내 공훈을 빼앗고자 한 건 네 쪽이잖나!
-Say all what you want, but it's all because you're a fool! -What kind of nonsense is that?! -Don't be stupid!
-잘도 지껄인다! 네가 멍청해서다! -뭔 하찮은 소리를 지껄이냐! -멍청한 소리 마라!
Forgive us!
용서를!
I won't let you alive next time. Reflect on yourselves.
이 다음에는 목숨은 없다. 당분간 반성하고 있어라.
Mr. Nobunaga.
노부나가 님.
-Hanzō. -Please leave me with finishing Musashi and others.
-한조. -무사시 일행의 처리는 이 제게 맡겨 주십시오.
Yes, good. But...
그래. 좋다. 다만...
I do not fail. Then!
실패는 하지 않습니다. 그럼!
Let me deal with hindrances first, and I'll sit on the seat of the king only after that.
일단 방해자를 처리하고 국왕의 의자에 앉을 것이다.
After being helped by Ryoma and his ship, Musashi and others split at a small island in Seto Inland Sea.
료마의 배로 도움을 받은 무사시 일행은 세토 내해의 작은 섬에서 떨어지게 되었다.
Mr. Ryoma! Thank you-dasu!
료마 씨! 신세졌소!
Let's look for a place to stay first.
그럼 일단 어딘가에 묵을 곳을 찾아봅시다.
Good idea. I want to take a rest in a bath.
그러자. 나 느긋하게 목욕탕에 들어가고 싶어.
Hot springs would be good! My shoulders are stiff lately.
온천이 좋지! 나, 최근 어깨가 뻐근해서!
That would be the best!
그럴 수 있으면 최고겠네!
Right, right!
그래그래!
What are you talking about? There's no way an inn like that would exist on this small island. Really...
뭔 소리입니까. 그런 여관이 이 작은 섬에 있을 리가 없잖아요. 정말...
Everyone, scatter!
다들! 갈라져!
Are they not going to allow us even a short break?
우리에게 느긋하게 쉴 틈도 안 주겠다는 건가!
Damn! There's no end to this!
젠장! 이대로는 끝이 없어!
Get rid of them as soon as possible and let's go to a hot spring!
어서 처리하고 온천 가자!
I know that!
알아!
Kerokichi!
케로키치!
Kerokichi! Fire tadpole bombs!
케로키치! 올챙이 폭탄 발사!
Are you alright-dasu, Otsuru?
괜찮소, 오츠루?
A string of my straw sandal is broken.
짚신 끈이 끊어졌어.
Then I'll carry you on my back-dasu!
그럼 내가 업어 주겠소!
Yes!
응!
Being friendly is good, eh?
사이가 좋은 건 좋은 것이구나?
Of course-dasu! We're lovers that everyone envies-dasu!
당연하오. 우리는 사람들이 부러워하는 애인들이니까.
No, Mr. Musashi, you're making me shy!
저런, 무사시 씨도 참, 오츠루 부끄럽게!
Is that so-dasu?
그렇소?
Hmph. Your playtime is over.
흥. 놀고 있는 것도 지금뿐이다.
Mr. Musashi, I'm scared!
무사시 씨, 무서워!
Leave it to me-dasu!
내게 맡기시오!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
이천일류 섬광권!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
Damn!
젠장!
I told you I'm invincible!
난 불사신이라 했을 터!
Time to finish!
끝장이다!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
Are you alright, Musashi?
괜찮냐, 무사시!
Jiraiyan! You saved me-dasu!
지라이얀! 살았소!
Kerokichi!
케로키치!
How dare you!
감히 어디서!
Jiraiyan! It seems that it was my mistake of letting you alive!
지라이얀! 널 살려둔 게 내 실수였던 듯 하구나!
That's right! Kerokichi, do it!
바로 그거다! 케로키치, 해라!
I'll come again!
다시 오겠다!
You can stop coming back-dasu!
더는 안 와도 되오!
Mr. Musashi, are you okay?
무사시 씨, 괜찮아?
Of course-dasu!
물론이오!
Damn, I want an invincible armor like that-dasu.
젠장! 나도 저런 불사신의 갑옷을 원하오.
Where's the enemy?!
적은 어딨냐!
Kojirō, you're very late.
코지로도 참, 엄청 늦게 왔어.
My, I was thinking to show my cool looks, and too bad.
저런, 기껏 내 멋진 모습을 보여주겠다고 생각했더니 안타깝군.
Instead of that, I brought a person that will make everyone happy.
그 대신, 모두가 기뻐할 사람을 데리고 왔습니다.
Huh? Is it Boss Zenigatan-dasu?
어? 제니가탄 두목이오?
It's the Highness, right?
국왕 전하지?
Could it be a cute girl living around Seto Inland Sea?
아니, 세토 내해의 귀여운 아이 아니야?
Is it dango store's boss?
단고집 주인이지?
No, you're wrong.
아니, 아닙니다.
I hurried my way from Edotopia because I was worried about Senhime.
센히메 님이 걱정되어 에도토피아에서 급히 왔습니다.
It seems that you people aren't really happy that I'm here.
여러분은 별로 기뻐하지 않는 것 같군요.
-I didn't know! -We're happy!
-몰랐어! -기뻐!
Who's there?!
누구냐!
A monster?!
괴물인가!
I am the protector of this island. I am here to send whoever came to disturb the island.
나는 이 섬의 수호신이다. 섬을 어지럽히러 온 자를 지옥에 보내러 왔다.
If you value your lives, then leave this island immediately!
목숨을 원한다면 어서 이 섬에서 떠나라!
We're not here to disturb the island!
우리는 섬을 어지럽히러 온 게 아니야!
We're here to expel the evil that disturbs the world!
세상을 어지럽히는 악을 퇴치하러 왔다!
Oh, they're children.
어라, 아이들이잖아.
I'm sorry. I thought you were that monster's friend.
미안해. 너희들이 그 괴물의 친구라고 생각했어.
Do you mean Megaton Castle by monster?
괴물이라는 것은 메가톤성 말입니까.
That's right.
그렇습니다.
In recent years, it's been ravaging through the bordering sea, and we couldn't even go fishing.
요즘 일이년, 이 주변 바다를 휩쓸고 다녀서 낚시도 불가능하게 되었습니다.
Some people left the island and went to big cities.
이 중에는, 섬을 버리고 도시로 나간 사람도 있습니다.
How cruel!
정말 못됐어!
Leave it to me-dasu. I'll deal with them-dasu!
내게 맡기시오. 꼭 해치워 주겠소!
You don't look so dependable...
별로 신뢰가 안 가는데.
Well, he doesn't look very dependable, but anyway, we came from Edotopia to get rid of Megaton Castle. Do not worry.
뭐, 어느 정도 믿음직스럽지 못한 면이 있지만, 저희는 메가톤성을 퇴치하러 에도토피아에서 왔습니다. 걱정하실 필요 없습니다.
Thank you. I'd like to invite you samurais to a different room to discuss something about that.
감사드립니다. 그것과 관계된 이야기지만, 사무라이 씨들을 별실에 모시고 싶습니다.
Alright.
좋습니다.
Good.
예.
Right.
응.
dasu.
그렇소.
This is an old document handed down from our ancestors which is left by the saviors from Planet Kara.
이건 선조에게서 대대로 전해지는 카라 별에서 온 구세주가 남기고 간 고문서입니다.
Planet Kara? Are you talking about the one floating on the sky?
카라 별? 하늘에 떠 있는 별 말입니까.
They say that a long time ago, Kara people riding on the Floating Ship of Sky came to this Onogoro Island.
먼 옛날, 하늘의 부주에 탄 카라인이 이 오노고로 섬에 왔다고 합니다.
Are you saying that they're aliens?
즉, 우주인입니까?
Aliens?
우주인?
Back then, the people of Onogoro Island were suffering from a fearful monster.
그 쯤, 오노고노 섬의 사람들은 두려운 괴물에 시달리고 있었다고 합니다.
That time, people from Planet Kara, descended from the Floating Ship of Sky, exterminated those, letting peace return.
그 때, 하늘의 부주에서 강림한 카라 별의 사람이 이걸 퇴치해서 이 섬에 평화가 되돌아왔습니다.
When the people of Onogoro Island suffer, brave people will come from the east,
이 오노고로 섬의 사람들이 고통받는 때, 용자가 동방에서 와서 범고래의 입에서 신의 갑주를 얻어 악을 물리치리라.
We the people of Onogoro Island are suffering. And brave people, you, have came from the east.
지금 저희 오노고로 섬 사람들은 고통받고 있습니다. 그리고 동쪽에서 용자인 당신들이 왔습니다.
Just like the prophecy said, right?
예고된 대로라는 말씀이십니까.
But you will need the armor of gods in order to take the monster down.
그러나 괴물을 쓰러트리는 데에는 신의 갑주가 필요합니다.
Huh? Are there armors-dasu? I want an armor that will let me not be defeated by Hanzō-dasu!
어? 갑주가 있소? 나, 한조에게 지지 않을 무적의 갑주를 원하오!
How expensive is that-dasu?
그거 얼마이오?
It's free.
공짜입니다.
Yay! I like whatever that's free-dasu!
아싸! 나, 공짜는 뭐든 좋소!
But you will have to enter the Mouth of Orc in order to claim those armors.
그러나 갑주를 손에 넣기 위해서는 범고래의 입에 들어가야만 합니다.
The Mouth of Orc-dasu?
범고래의 입이오?
Will they be able to get the armors? Wait for the stormy latter half!
갑주를 손에 넣을 수 있을 것인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Below here is the Mouth of Orc.
이 아래가 범고래의 입입니다.
This is very high-dasu! Are we going down from this place-dasu?
엄청 높소. 여기서 내려가오?
No, it's impossible from here. Because of a strong wind from the seaside, you'll be thrown away.
아니, 여기서는 무리입니다. 해면에서 올라오는 강풍 때문에 날라가버리고 맙니다.
Then, how can we go there-dasu?
그럼 어떻게 저기까지 가오?
You have to use a ship.
배로 갈 수밖에 없습니다.
You will ride a ship from a cape on the other side, follow the water current, and reach the Mouth of Orc.
건너편의 곶에서 배에 타, 해류를 타고 범고래의 입까지 다다를 수 있습니다.
But the current crashes strongly into the Mouth of Orc, thus the ship will be broken into pieces if you don't make it.
그러나 범고래의 입에서는 해류가 강하게 부딪히고 있어서, 기회를 놓치면 바위에 부딪혀서 배는 엉망이 됩니다.
Please be careful!
조심하세요!
Do not die!
죽으면 안 돼!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
Everyone, do your best!
다들 힘내!
We're letting the rope go!
밧줄을 놓습니다!
I won't forgive you if you die there!
그런 곳에서 죽으면 용서 못 해!
Kojirō!
코지로!
Everyone, are you hurt?
여러분, 상처는 없습니까.
I'm not hurt, but it's heavy-dasu.
상처는 없어도, 나, 무겁소.
But still, we live because there's a log in an awesome place.
그래도 마침 좋은 곳에 통나무가 있어서 살았습니다.
It's not a log! It's Kerokichi's tongue!
통나무가 아니야! 케로키치 혀야!
Kerokichi! Extend your tongue into the Mouth of Orc!
케로키치! 이대로 범고래의 입까지 혀를 늘려!
Hey, it could've been easier if you did that at the first place!
뭐야, 처음부터 그랬으면 간단했잖아!
But Mr. Kerokichi looks painful.
그래도 케로키치 씨, 힘들어 보여요.
We did it-dasu!
해냈소!
I'll give up the armor! You three can go by yourselves!
난 갑주를 포기할게! 셋이서 가!
Jiraiyan, you can't give up-dasu! Come here-dasu!
지라이얀! 포기하면 안 되오! 여기에 오시오!
There isn't enough time! Musashi, look below you!
이제 시간이 없어! 무사시, 발밑을 봐!
The water's flowing in-dasu.
아까보다 물이 들어왔소.
High tide...
만조인가.
Mr. Musashi, unless we claim the armors soon, we won't be able to get out of the cave.
무사시 님, 어서 갑주를 손에 놓지 않으면 이 동굴에서 나가지 못하게 됩니다.
Got it-dasu.
알겠소.
Everyone! Find the armor no matter what!
다들 꼭 갑주를 찾아내!
You woke up, Kerokichi.
정신 차렸구나, 케로키치.
I don't need armors.
난 갑주는 필요 없어.
Because I have you.
네가 있으니까.
So many skulls-dasu...
해골이 가득이오...
It seems that numerous martial artists came into this cave, hearing that rumor.
다수의 무예가가 소문을 듣고 이 동굴에 들어온 것 같군요.
But most of them didn't make it through, and died.
그래도 대부분이 관문을 못 넘고 죽고 말았다.
It seems that the legend is true.
보아하니 전설은 진짜 같구나.
You guys really are trying your best to look calm, in a situation like this-dasu.
잘도 그런 상황에서 침착하고 있소.
Well, excuse us.
저런, 이건 곤란하군요.
There's a light-dasu!
빛이 있소!
Woah, this is big-dasu!
와, 크오!
Judging from the look that I never saw before, it must be an alien.
본 적도 없는 모습을 보아하니 분명 우주인일 것입니다.
But, I can't see an armor around here.
그래도 갑주는 어디에도 없군요.
Is it only a legend, after all?
역시 전설뿐인 것인가...
Well, we're here, so...
뭐, 기껏 왔으니...
Let us finish Nobunaga and others. Let me marry Otsuru.
노부나가 놈들을 해치울 수 있도록. 그리고 오츠루하고 결혼할 수 있도록.
It seems that there was a sound-reactive device installed.
음, 소리에 반응하는 장치가 설치되어 있었던 것 같군요.
Alright! Let's go-dasu!
좋소! 가 보오!
What was that for-dasu, Kojirō?!
뭔 짓이오, 코지로!
Sorry. I'm weak to rats...
미안. 난 생쥐에 약해서...
Mr. Musashi! Mr. Kojirō!
무사시 님! 코지로 님!
Standing in the middle of this light, a strange feeling is arising.
이 빛 가운데에 서니, 뭔가 이상한 감정이 들끓어 오릅니다.
A strange feeling?
이상한 감정이라니?
Just like as if I'm embraced in the bosom of my mother.
그래, 마치 어머님의 품에 안긴 느낌의.
Should I explain more?
더 말해 볼까요?
-Then, me too. -Me too.
-그럼 나도. -나도.
I was waiting for you, brave ones. Only the ones with the mind of justice can reach here.
용자들이여, 기다리고 있었다. 옳은 마음을 가진 자만이 이 곳에 올 수 있다.
W- what is this-dasu?
이, 이게 무엇이오?
(Gentoku: Japanese pronunciation of Xuande, the courtesy name of Liu Bei)
(겐토쿠: 현덕, 유비의 자)
Armor of Gentoku.
현덕의 갑주.
(Kan'u: Guan Yu; served Liu Bei)
(칸우: 관우)
Armor of Kanu.
관우의 갑주.
(Chōhi: Zhang Fei; served Liu Bei)
(초히: 장비)
Armor of Chohi.
장비의 갑주.
(raimei: thunder)
그리고 그대에게는 뇌명환을 건네 주겠다.
The armor will show itself when you're about to exterminate the evil with the spirit of justice,
그 갑주, 옳은 마음으로 악을 쓰러트리고자 할 때 나타나지만, 보통의 배에 달하는 에너지를 소모한다는 것을 잊지 말지어다.
That was close-dasu!
위험했소!
Look!
저건!
Senhime!
센히메 님!
Mr. Musashi!
무사시 씨!
I'm sorry. I couldn't protect them...
미안, 다들. 내가 지켜야 했는데...
I was waiting for you, Musashi, Kojirō, and Jūbee. You three are going to the other world this instant!
기다리고 있었다, 무사시, 코지로, 주베. 셋이서 한꺼번에 저 세상에 보내 주겠다!
That's cowardly, Hanzō!
비겁하오, 한조!
Cowardly? I hear that a lot.
비겁해? 그건 언제라도 듣는 소리지.
I'll beat your twisted guts into shape-dasu!
그 틀려먹은 근성을 때려고쳐 주겠소!
Drop your swords, Musashi!
칼을 버려라, 무사시!
The rage towards evil mind is boiling-dasu!
악한 마음을 향한 분노가 들끓어오르오!
Karakuri Shift! Gentoku Armor!
카라쿠리 변화! 겐토쿠 아머!
Musashi! When did you get that armor?!
무사시! 언제 그런 갑주를!
Karakuri Shift! Kanu Armor!
카라쿠리 변화! 칸우 아머!
Even you, Kojirō?!
어, 코지로까지!
Karakuri Shift! Chohi Armor!
카라쿠리 변화! 초히 아머!
Even Jūbee got an armor!
주베까지 갑주를!
Hanzō! Prepare yourself-dasu!
한조! 각오하시오!
Three against one is cowardly!
나 혼자에게 셋이서 덤비다니 비겁하다!
Hmph! I never thought we'd be hearing that from you-dasu!
흥! 네게 그런 소리 들을 거라고는 생각도 못 했소!
Yeah, right!
그래라!
I'll let you go for today!
오늘은 이쯤에서 봐 주겠다!
Hmph! A big talk for an unskilled-dasu!
흥! 잘하는 것도 없는 주제에 뭔 소리이오.
Here are your dinners!
자, 다들, 저녁이야!
So delicious-dasu! Fighting in armors makes me hungry-dasu!
우와, 맛있소! 갑주를 입고 싸우니 배가 고프오!
Anyway, your armors look so cool!
그래도 정말 멋진 갑주야!
Yeah, I was moved!
응, 나, 감동했어!
Mr. Jūbee, do you need more?
주베 씨, 더 드실래요?
I'd like more. Thank you.
아, 감사합니다. 부탁드립니다.
That was good! Kerokichi, you should eat a lot, too!
잘 먹었다! 케로키치, 많이 먹어라!
A cup of tea after a battle is tremendous.
음, 전투 후의 한 잔의 차는 아주 그만이구나.
Kojirō, you sound like an old man on a side street!
저런, 코지로도 참, 골목 할배같아!
Oh, do you think so?
아니, 그렇습니까.
Their enemy Hanzō has regrettably ran away.
숙적 한조는 아깝게도 달아났다. 그러나 무사시 일행은 무적의 갑주를 손에 넣어서 용기 100배가 되었다.
Until you destroy the ambition of Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh, go, fight, Musashi! That's the heyday of a man!
육도마왕 노부나가의 야망을 깨뜨릴 때까지, 가라, 싸워라, 무사시! 그게 사내의 전성기이다!
I fought and I got beaten
싸우고 맞았어
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
I can't lose, so take my blow!
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Next is delightful lunchtime
다음 시간 즐거운
But it's not delightful today
급식일 텐데
The thunder of my teacher
선생님의 벼락이
only hit me and nobody else
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
I tried to explain
사정을 말해도
But he won't listen
들어주지 않는 채
Now whatever I do
어떻게 해도 역시
I end up crying
눈물이 나오고 말아
Don't cry when you eat, or
울면서 밥먹으면
it tastes totally bad
완전 맛없어
you'll feel downhearted
왠지 안타까워
We asked an inventor named Mr. Gennai to make a submarine for us-dasu.
우리는 겐나이 씨라는 발명가에게 잠수함을 만들어 달라고 부탁했소.
But that old man is lewd-dasu. He wants to see Osenchan and Otsuru in swimsuits-dasu.
그래도 그 할아버지, 호색하오. 오센짱하고 오츠루의 수영복 모습을 보여달라고 하오.
Well, whatever, the submarine is complete and we invade into Megaton Castle-dasu!
그래도, 뭐, 잠수함도 완성되어서 우리는 메가톤성에 침입하오!
Next story! Surfing Gennai is the Invention King
다음 이야기! 파도타는 겐나이 발명왕이오
It's a stormy submarine-dasu!
질풍노도의 잠수함이오!
Next Episode
다음 이야기
Surfing Gennai
파도타는 겐나이
is the Invention King
발명왕이오
Look forwards for it!
기대하세요!